Francesca is the princess of Norsteinberg, a small country in Europe.
Bored and sheltered, she escapes her butler's watchful eyes while traveling.
She meets a thief, Don Pierre.
Francesca keeps fighting with this playboy,
but she accidentally discovers that he really is her blood brother.
Now, the secret society "Black Rose Squad" is after them!
Will Francesca be able to adjust to society after being a slacker for so long?
What about Jyunichi and Satoru's forbidden love?
That is totally not true! Not even close!
Ohh... Anime is such a wonderful thing!
Hey!
[New Staff at Snack House Otose, moe character with cat ears?]
[Is Shinpachi afraid of fried eggs? Kagura is always drowsy.]
♪♪～
The flower-lined path to the stage of the floating world
(来宮 良子)＜浮世舞台の花道は➡
[Narrator: Ryoko Kinomiya]
表もあれば 裏もある｡
has both a top side, and a bottom side.
Those whose lives blossom have their songs,
花と咲く身に 歌あれば➡
and for those whose lives do not, songs are all they have.
咲かぬ花にも 歌ひとつ｡
今日も今日とて 悲しい男女｡
Today, as everyday, lonely men and women
wander about, bringing their cold bodies together at a place
寒い体を寄せ合うように➡
where they laugh while hiding their tears with their drinks.
流れ流れて 落ち合う先は➡
[Snack House]
酒で 涙を隠して笑う 小さなｽﾅｯｸ｡
A tiny snack house.
光が漏れる扉から➡
Light spilling through its door.
[Snack House]
The music sinks deeply into their hearts.
なぜか身に染む 心唄＞
♪♪～
[Kabukicho 1st Street]
(ﾊﾟﾄｶｰのｻｲﾚﾝ)
Stop! You bastard!
(警官)止まれ この野郎！
Man, I'm so drunk.
(ﾑｰさん)あぁ 酔った酔った…｡
(お登勢)足元 気をつけなよ
ﾑｰさん｡
Watch your step, Mu.
You've had quite a lot to drink.
(お登勢)ｱﾝﾀ かなり飲んでるよ｡
That's nothing!
なぁに こんくらい
飲んだうちに入んねえって｡
You can't even call that "drinking."
(ﾑｰさん)また来るよ｡
I'll come back again.
You're the only one, Otose, who listens to my stories.
ｵﾚの話 聞いてくれんのは
お登勢さんだけだからな｡
I don't know what you're talking about. I turn away boring customers!
なに言ってんだか｡
ｳﾁは ｼｹた客は お断りだよ！
Yes, yes, I know.
(ﾑｰさん)は～い！ っと｡
ﾌｯ｡
…ん？
Meow.
≪(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ﾐｬｱ～｡
なんだ 野良猫かい｡
Oh, it's just a stray cat.
腹が空いてんのかい？
Are you hungry?
Come on in.
おいで 店の残り物でいいなら
何か食べさせてやるよ｡
If the bar's leftovers are okay with you, then I'll feed you some.
[People Who Make Good First Impressions Usually Suck]
あぁ!? ｱﾝﾀの口は➡
Can't your mouth say anything other than "wait on the rent"?
｢家賃を待ってくれ｣しか
しゃべれないのかい！
(お登勢)いいかげん
聞き飽きたよ｡
I'm sick and tired of hearing that.
At least once in a while, couldn't you say, "advance payment,"
たまには
｢前払い｣だの ｢お礼｣だの➡
or "thank you," or "you're looking beautiful as usual."
｢今日も お美しいですね｣だの
しゃべれないもんかね？
You're so inconsiderate.
気が利かないねぇ｡
If all I have to do is say it, I'll say it all you want.
(銀時)しゃべるだけなら
しゃべってやらぁ｡ たかが…➡
It's just "You're looking beautiful...as usual."
今日も お美し～い～｡
…ﾀﾞﾒだ お口が ｲﾔ ｲﾔ ｲﾔ～ﾝ｡
I can't do it. My mouth is saying "No, no, no!"
そんな役立たずな口
縫い合わせちまいな！
Such a useless mouth. You should sew it shut!
(お登勢)ｱﾀｼが やってやろうか？
ﾀｺ糸と布団針で｡ あぁ？
Shall I do it for you? With a kite string and a needle?
Go away! My mouth is for strawberry milk and chocolate parfaits.
うっせえ｡ ｵﾚの口はな➡
いちご牛乳と ﾁｮｺﾚｰﾄﾊﾟﾌｪのために
あるんだよ！
そんな乳くさいもん
飲んでる暇があるなら➡
If you have the time to drink baby stuff like that, then cough up some of the rent you owe!
１円でもいいから
家賃を払いなってんだよ！
家賃より ｵﾚの人生のほうが
大事なんだよ｡
My life is more important than rent.
ｸｯ… ｱﾝﾀ ｱﾎだね｡
You're an idiot.
ｱﾎの上に ｢ど｣がつくね！
An idiot with "stupid" on top for good measure.
なんなら ｢ｸｿ｣もつけてやろうか！
I'll add "shitty" too, if you like. You shitty stupid idiot.
この ｸｿどｱﾎ～!!
あ～っ ｱﾎっていうのは
言ったﾔﾂのほうがｱﾎなんだぜ！
Oh yeah! It takes one to know one, you know!
Idiot, idiot, idiot.
ｱﾎｱﾎ！ ｱﾎ～｡
It's not just your taste buds. Are your brains at the level of a preschooler, too?
(お登勢)味覚だけじゃなくて
脳味噌も 幼稚園児なみかい！
あん？
(神楽)おかわり よろし？
Extra helpings?
ﾒｼを飲むな！
ｳﾁは 定食屋じゃ
ねえんだっつうの！
This ain't no lunch counter, you get me?
Stop drinking your rice!
さっきから お前
ﾒｼ 食ってんじゃなくて➡
For a while now, you haven't been eating your rice, you've been drinking it!
This is a place for creepy old men to
飲んでんじゃねえか！
ここは 酒と 健全なｴﾛを➡
simultaneously drink themselves sick and indulge their sick minds.
A meal isn't a sport!
A "Snack" house, If you catch my meaning!
楽しむ場所 ｽﾅｯｸなんだよ！
ﾒｼは ｽﾎﾟｰﾂじゃねえんだぞ!!
炭を入れて炊くと
ｶﾙｷ臭さが とれるね｡
If you put charcoal inside and cook it, the chlorine smell goes away.
おばあちゃんの知恵袋ｱﾙ｡
It's a pearl of wisdom from my grandmother.
Are you trying to suck up to me?
それで 恩を売ったつもりかい？
In a roundabout way, you're saying it doesn't taste good.
遠まわしに ｢ﾏｽﾞｲ｣って
言ってるんじゃないか｡
普通 ﾒｼ食うときの効果音は
｢ﾊﾟｸﾊﾟｸ｣だろうが｡
Normally, the sound you make when you eat rice is pakupaku,
お前のは…｡
(新八)あっ！
but in your case...
Oh!
You fool!
ﾊﾞｶ！ ここで いちばん高いのは
嘘で塗り固めた笑顔じゃなくて➡
The most expensive thing here is not the smile that seals a lie.
つきだしの乾き物だぁ～！
It's those dried garnishes!
家賃とは別に つけとくからね｡
I'll add it separately to your rent.
N-No way...
そ… そんな…｡
For guys who can't wipe their own backsides, helping other people is ludicrous.
(お登勢)自分で
ｹﾂも ふけないようなﾔﾂが➡
人の面倒みようなんて
ちゃんちゃら おかしいね｡
I never could reach around back there.
体が硬いのは 生まれつきだよ｡
少しくらい残っていたって
いいだろ｡
You could at least leave a little for us.
そのｹﾂじゃねえ｡
I didn't mean it literally.
乾き物は のど渇くｱﾙね｡ ｳｰﾛﾝ茶｡
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)はい｡
Dried foods make me thirsty.
Oolong tea, please.
Yes.
…って ｽｰﾊﾟｰだったら
ﾍﾟｯﾄﾎﾞﾄﾙ 358円のｳｰﾛﾝ茶を➡
Why drink oolong tea here when you can get it at the supermarket
in a plastic bottle for 358 yen?!
なんで ここで飲みますか!!
That's as outrageous as some rich guy who burns a wad of bills
玄関で 札束燃やして 靴 探す
成金ｵﾔｼﾞなみの暴挙ですよ！
in the foyer looking for his shoes!
Do something about her!
なんとかしましょうよ｡
このままじゃ➡
At this rate, all the money in the world isn't going to be enough!
お金なんて
いくらあっても足りませんよ！
Not that we ever had any.
いや… もともと ないですけどね｡
あぁ… ねぇ｡
Yeah, you're right.
We could work honest jobs!
ﾏｼﾞﾒに働くとか！
あ～｡
Yeah.
いっそ ﾏｼﾞﾒに踏み倒しとか！
Or we could seriously walk out on our bills!
あ～｡
Yeah.
こ… こうなりゃ ﾔｹだ｡
ｱﾝﾀを殺して ﾎﾞｸも死ぬ!!
At this point, I'm desperate!
I'll kill you and take my own life, too!
…ぐぇっ!!
落ち着け｡
Calm down.
How apathetic can you be?!
…あぁ もう！
なんて無気力なんだ！
物事に立ち向かう勇気どころか
逃げる決意さえ できないなんて｡
You can't even decide to run away,
much less have the courage to stand up to something!
父親不在の現代教育のひずみが
ここに…！
うるせえなぁ｡
The stress of modern education without a father is showing up here!
Aw, shut up!
元服したら
親の責任じゃねえんだよ｡
Once you've come of age, it isn't your parents' fault anymore.
Do something about it yourself.
ﾃﾒｴ自身で 何とかしろ｡
何とかなってないじゃないですか
家賃…！
You haven't done anything about the rent!
うるさいｱﾙ｡
Pipe down.
親が死んでも 食休みっと｡
Even if your parents die, you still have to eat and rest.
やれやれ｡
Good grief.
Blood! Blood!
血が～！ 血がぁ～っ!!
Blood!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)あの… 大丈夫ですか？
え？
Uh...are you all right?
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)
これで押さえるといいですよ｡
Press on it with this.
あら 初めて見る顔だな｡
新入りか？
Haven't seen your face before.  You new here?
Yes. I've been working here from a while back. I'm Catherine.
はい この間から
働かせていただいてます➡
ｷｬｻﾘﾝいいます｡
彼女 出稼ぎで
ここに来たｸﾁでねぇ｡
She came to earth to make some money.
実家に仕送りするために
頑張ってんだ｡
She works hard to send money back home.
Pleased to meetchu.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)よろしくお願いしまっす｡
She's good with the customers, and does a good job.
客あしらいは うまいし
よくやってくれてるよ｡
とんでもはっぷん
歩いて10分です｡
It's no big deal at all.
大したもんだ｡
そのうえ ｷﾞｬｸﾞのｾﾝｽも侮れない｡
That's impressive.
And she even has a great sense of humor.
え～？ そう？
Oh? Really?
Someone around here has absolutely no talent for humor.
どっかの誰かなんて
ﾂｯｺﾐはできんし ﾎﾞｹも無理！
The other one lives only to satisfy her hunger.
もう１人は 己の食欲を
満たすためだけに… ぐわっ!!
う～ん もう食べられないね…｡
I can't eat any more.
(銀時たち)そりゃ そうだろうよ｡
Of course not.
じゃあ つらいことも
しんどいことも➡
Well, there may be difficult moments, tough moments and unbearable moments,
耐えられないことも
あるだろうけど…➡
but hang in there.
頑張って｡
ありがとございます｡
Thank you very much.
今が つらいと思っても➡
You might think things are difficult now,
but in the future, it's gonna get a lot worse.
この先 もっともっと
つらいことが あるからな｡
If you keep that in mind, you can endure it.
それを思えば
耐えられるってもんだ｡
ｱﾝﾀ 真性のﾏｿﾞですか！
What are you, a genuine masochist?
(ﾏﾏ)また いらしてね～｡
Come back soon.
(ﾏﾏ)あの 天下り野郎が！
You golden parachute bastard!
…ん？
…あぁっ！
The money!
(ﾏﾏ)売り上げがぁ～っ!!
(ﾗｰﾒﾝ屋)う… 売り上げが…｡
Th-The money...
The money!
(ﾎｽﾄ)売り上げが…！
♪♪～
I'm so hungry...so hungry.
ひもじいよ～｡ ひもじいよ～｡
Shut up.
うっせえなぁ｡ だったら
家に帰りゃいいだろうが｡
Then why don't you just go home!
You probably have food there.
食いもんだって あるだろうによ｡
My sister is home today.
今日は 姉上がいるんですよ｡
ん？
姉上がいて
食事の支度をしてるんですよ｡
My sister's there, cooking.
(お妙の鼻歌)
Shin, today we're having fried egg
((お妙:新ちゃん
今日のご飯は…➡
卵焼きと… 卵焼きと卵焼きよ))
and fried egg and fried egg.
Sis's fried eggs make me see things I'm not supposed to see.
姉上の卵焼きは 食べると➡
見えちゃいけないものまで
見えてくるんです｡
Did you know, Gin?
銀さん 知ってますか？
A kind of canned herring called Surströmming
ｼｭｰﾙｽﾄﾚﾐﾝｸﾞって ﾆｼﾝの缶詰は➡
has a smell that even cats run away from.
猫ですら逃げ出す
においらしいですよ｡
They say smelly things taste good.
臭いものはうまいって
いいますもんね｡
Gin, did you know?
銀さん 知ってますか？
The Inuit people, after killing a caribou,
ｲﾇｲｯﾄの人たちは
ﾄﾅｶｲを倒したら➡
apparently eat even the gunky contents of the stomach.
ﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛ～になった胃の内容物も
ちゃんと食べるらしいですよ｡
It must be warm and delicious.
あったかくて やわらかくて
おいしいんだろうなぁ｡
Gin, did you know?
銀さん 知ってますか？
When an owl catches a baby mouse,
ﾌｸﾛｳは 子ﾈｽﾞﾐを さらってきたら
自分の巣の中で➡
it feeds it to fatten it in its nest before eating it.
ｴｻあげて 太らせてから
食べるらしいですよ｡
It must be plump and juicy for sure.
ﾌﾟﾘｯﾌﾟﾘですよね きっと｡
There are so many delicious things in the world.
世界には うまいものが
いっぱいあるっていうのになぁ｡
よく考えたら ここの家賃って➡
When I think about it, the rent here isn't all that low, is it?
そんなに
安くないんじゃないですか？
There must be a ton of other places that are cheaper than this.
ここより安いところなんて
ざらにあるはずですよ｡
You know, Gin...
ねぇ 銀さん｡
あれ～～っ!?
What the?!
Our emergency funds!
緊急用予算が！
That borderline-diabetic rat bastard!
あの 糖尿寸前野郎～っ!!
(ﾑｰさん)でね ｵﾚは
なんて いい会社に➡
I thought I got into a really great company!
入ったんだ と
思ったわけよ そんときは｡
At that time anyway.
あら… ﾀﾊﾞｺ｡
Huh? Where're my cigarettes?
Oh come now. You just sent Catherine out to buy some.
やだよ｡ さっき ｷｬｻﾘﾝに
買いにいかせたじゃないのさ｡
あら そうだっけか？
What? Did I?
そうだよ｡ まったくもう｡
Yes, you did. You're too much.
(ﾊﾟﾄｶｰのｻｲﾚﾝ)
She sure is taking long, though. How far did that girl go?
…にしても遅いねぇ｡
あの子 どこまで行ってんだか｡
♪♪～
Hey.
よっ｡
おつかいか？
ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ 人使いが荒いからなぁ｡
On an errand? That old hag is a real taskmaster.
Y-Yes, I am. I came to buy Mu's cigarettes...
そ そうです｡ ﾑｰさんのﾀﾊﾞｺ買いに｡
そうか｡
I see.
すみません すみません｡
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Anyway, this area is
まぁ この辺りはなぁ…➡
ｺﾞﾐための 掃き溜めの
吹き溜まりみたいなとこだ｡
like a garbage dump where the trash piles up.
What I want to say is...
何を言いたいかってぇと➡
the two of us are alike, we're both trash.
ｵﾚたちは
同じ ｺﾞﾐどうしってことだ｡
No, trash isn't the right word.
いや ｺﾞﾐってのは
ちょっと違ってだな…➡
We're both boogers in the same nostril.
同じ穴の鼻ｸｿ…｡
In the same pot...pan...spoon.
同じ釜… 鍋 おたま…｡
I understand.
わかります｡
あなた いい人｡ みんな いい人｡
You're a good person. All of you are good people.
You both from around here?
(同心)ｱﾝﾀら ここの人？
だったら？
What's it to you?
こういうもんなんだけど｡
Have a look.
…で？
So?
ちょっと 捜査に
協力してもらえない？
Can I get you to cooperate with an investigation?
Is this everyone?
これで 全員？
Did something happen?
(お登勢)何かあったのかい？
(同心)うん ちょっとね｡
Yes, there have been
この辺でさ 店の売り上げを
持ち逃げされる事件が➡
several robberies in the vicinity.
多発してるんだよね｡
え…？
(岡っ引き)今月に入って
16件ですね｡
Sixteen since the start of this month.
That's pretty troubling.
そりゃ 憂慮すべき事態ですな｡
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
Says the thief who stole the money!
…って 金盗った張本人が！
It's obvious by that sweet breath of yours?
それに その 目に見えてわかる
甘ったるい息は何だ!?
The perp appears to be an Amanto.
(同心)犯人は 天人らしいんだが
まだ捜査中でね｡
It's still under investigation.
なんか 気になる噂とか
ないかと思ってね｡
I thought you might have heard any disturbing rumors.
In that case, I have heard one.
それなら 知ってますよ～｡
She's your suspect.
犯人は ｺｲﾂです！
いやぁ～～っ!!
What the hell did you do that for?!
お… お前！
なに さらしてくれとんじゃい!!
冗談が つまらない人は➡
Man who makes bad jokes get finger broken.
指を折られるｱﾙ｡
知るか～っ!!
Never heard of that!
I was just trying to show you a way to return to your hometown for free.
ｵﾚが せっかく
ﾀﾀﾞで故郷に帰る方法を➡
教えてやろうと思ったのに｡
いや…
強制送還は ﾀﾀﾞではないよ｡
Deportation isn't free.
No sir, I'd be returning home in disgrace.
まったくｱﾙ｡ そんな 不名誉な帰国
ごめんこうむるｱﾙ｡
選んでる立場か！
You're in no position to be choosy!
Worst comes to worst, I'll just hold onto the side of ship and go home like that.
いざとなれば
船にしがみついて 帰るｱﾙ｡
5...4...3...2...1...
((ｱﾅｳﾝｽ:５ ４ ３…｡
(係員)ﾉｰ！
No!
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)０！))
Zero!
(神楽)こっち来たときも
成功したｱﾙ｡
Did that on the trip here!
なんとかなるね｡
I'll manage!
って それ 冷たい方程式だから！
That's a cold calculation.
大丈夫｡ 宇宙に放り出しても
平気で生きられるから｡
I'll be fine.
Even if she's thrown out into space, she'll have no problem surviving.
I'm not a cockroach!
ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘじゃないね！
なんだぁ？ その言い方は！
How dare you say that!
Apologize to the cockroaches!
ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘさんに謝れ！
地球最高の生命力を誇る➡
Apologize to the cockroaches, the greatest survivors on Earth!
ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘさんに謝れ！
No way!
Am I...in the way here?
なんか ｵﾚ ｼﾞｬﾏ…？
Anyway, we don't have the kind of money that someone would steal.
(お登勢)少なくとも ｳﾁには
盗られるような大金も➡
盗るような悪人も いないからね｡
Well, if anything does happen, we'll let you know.
(お登勢)まぁ
何かあったら 知らせるよ｡
(同心)よろしく｡
Please do.
うっ… うぇ～…｡
The inside of my mouth tastes awful!
口ん中 気持悪ぃ～｡
I shouldn't drink sweet milk beverages just before going to bed.
やっぱ 寝しなに
甘い乳飲料なんか➡
飲むもんじゃねえなぁ｡
Okay, I've taken another step up towards becoming an adult.
よし ｵﾚは また１つ
大人の階段を上った｡
But I'm going down the steps.
…って 下りてんじゃねえかよ！
えっ なに １人で
ﾎﾞｹとﾂｯｺﾐやってんだよ｡
Why am I doing my own two-man comedy routine?
あ？ あれ 残業？
What? Working overtime?
Couldn't be.
んなわけねえか｡ …あ？
I'm starving.
お腹が減って… あ？
I'm sooooo sorry!
あぁっ！
すすすすすす… すみません!!
Forgive me for interrupting your midnight tryst!
真夜中の ただれた
情痴の世界に おｼﾞｬﾏして！
I'll disappear. Please enjoy your dazzling world of pleasure!
すぐに消えますから めくるめく
官能の世界を お楽しみください！
Hey.
おい｡
…あぁっ！
Dopes.
(神楽)愚民どもが～｡
Prostrate yourselves before my power.
私の力の前に
ひれ伏すがいい｡ ﾌﾊｯ ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
You're sleepwalking.
…って 寝ぼけてんの？
それ 何の夢？
What was that dream? What's it about?
A brandy glass and cat?
ﾌﾞﾗﾝﾃﾞｰｸﾞﾗｽと 猫？
How empty a man's life is.
(神楽)人の命とは
なんと むなしいものか～｡
Hey!
おい｡
だから それ どこの悪代官？
So what evil sheriff was that?
…あれ？
Huh?
それ ｵﾚの原ﾁｬﾘに似てるな｡
That looks like my scooter.
いい人ばっかりね｡
You're all good people.
Now that you mention it, the umbrella in the back looks exactly like mine.
そういえば 後ろに積んである傘
私のに そっくりｱﾙな｡
っつか あれ 店のﾚｼﾞ！
That's the bar's cash register!
What the hell are you doing at this hour of the night?
(お登勢)なんだい
こんな丑三つ時に… はっ！
♪♪～
ｷｬｻﾘﾝ！
Catherine?!
あばよ 腐れﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ！
Bye, rotten old hag.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ﾊﾞ～ｶ！
Moor-ons!
That ugly pig-faced cow!
Tonight, I drink your blood!
あの ﾌﾞｽ女～!!
血祭りじゃ～!!
♪♪～
(運転手)なんだぁ!?
(急ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ音)
Wh-What the?!
(おばさん)ｷｬｰｯ 助けて ｾｲﾔ！
(ｾｲﾔ)勘弁してください！
Help! Seiya!
Give me a break!
Just a minute. What're you guys doing?
ちょっ… 何やってんの!?
Where are you going?
どこ行くの!?
あ… 待って！
Waaaaaait!
They're gone.
行っちゃった…｡
行っちゃったよ おい！
They drove off! Dammit!
Seiya! I'm scared!
(おばさん)ｾｲﾔ 怖い！
(ｾｲﾔ)うっせえ！ ｺｽﾓ燃やすぞ!!
Shut up! Old hag!
♪♪～
(ﾗｰﾒﾝ屋)うわぁっ！
(ﾗｰﾒﾝ屋)なんだべ…？
What's that?
♪♪～
うおぉ～～っ！ 猫は ｲﾔ～ｯ!!
I hate cats!
(衝突音)
Hey! I think we just moved past Catherine in the felony count!
お～い！ なんか もう
ｷｬｻﾘﾝより➡
悪いことしてるんじゃないの？
ﾎﾞｸら！
There!
(神楽)あぁっ！ ｷｬｻﾘﾝ!!
Catherine!
Die!
死ねぇｱﾙ～！
Cath...er...ine!
(神楽)ｷｬｻﾘ～ﾝ!!
♪♪～
Deaaatthhhhh!
What? What?!
(銀時/新八/神楽)…あれ？
あれぇ～～っ!!
(お登勢)残念だよ｡
Too bad.
I rather liked you.
(お登勢)ｱﾀｼ ｱﾝﾀのこと
嫌いじゃなかったんでねぇ｡
家族のために働いてるって あれ…
あれも嘘なのかい？
That part about you supporting your family. Was that a lie, too?
Otose. You're a good person. But you're such a dope.
お登勢さん あなた いい人｡
でも ﾊﾞｶね｡
It's okay to like helping people.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)世話好き 結構｡
でも 度が過ぎると➡
But if you overdo it, bad people like me will take advantage of you.
私のような悪いﾔﾂに
つけこまれるね｡
It's part of my character.  Too late to change.
(お登勢)ｿｲﾂは 性分さね｡
もう直らんよ｡
でも…➡
It's how I got to meet some interesting people.
おかげで おもしろい連中とも
会えたんだがねぇ｡
Want to hear about it?
(お登勢)聞きたいかい？
No, hear me out. It's the least you can do.
いや 聞いていきな｡ せめてさ｡
There was a man, you see.
(お登勢)まず ある男は こうさ｡
It was a cold, snowy day.
(お登勢)雪の降る 寒い日だった｡
On a whim, I went out to visit my late husband's grave.
ｱﾀｼは 気まぐれに
旦那の墓参りに出かけたんだ｡
♪♪～
Hey, Granny!
((おい ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ｡
Mind if I eat those dumplings?
まんじゅう食べていい？
腹減って死にそうなんだ｡
I'm so hungry I'm about to croak.
These aren't for me. I gave them to my husband. Ask him.
こりゃ ｱﾀｼのじゃなくて
旦那にやったもんだよ｡
旦那に聞きな｡
Oh yeah?
あっそ｡ んじゃ｡
Okay, then...
何つってた？ ｱﾀｼの旦那))
What did my husband say?
When I asked him, do you know what he said?
(お登勢)そう聞いたら
ｿｲﾂ 何て答えたと思う？
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)さあね｡
他人の思い出話には 興味ない｡
Don't know.
I have no interest in the rambling of strangers.
｢死人が 口きくか｣ だとさ｡
"Dead men don't talk," he said.
"I won't ever forget this debt."
(お登勢)｢この恩は忘れねえ｡
"After all, you're an old lady. Probably going to kick the bucket soon."
ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ 老い先 短いんだろうが…➡
"But until that happens, I'll watch over her for you," he said.
この先は…➡
ｱﾝﾀの代わりに
ｵﾚが守ってやる｣ってさ｡
♪♪～
てやぁ～～っ!!
((ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
You're going to watch over me?
(お登勢)ｱﾝﾀが ｱﾀｼを守る？
Let's see what you can do, then.
(お登勢)お手並み拝見と
いこうじゃないか))
Nice way to show her gratitude to you for giving her a job.
仕事くれてやった恩を
仇で返すたぁよ➡
People who can't keep their obligations are simply hideous, old hag.
仁義を解さねえﾔﾂってのは
男も女も醜いねぇ ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ｡
Like someone who lives on the second floor of someone's house without paying rent?
(お登勢)家賃も払わずに
人んちの２階に➡
住み着いてるﾔﾂは
醜くないのかい？
People are all kind of hideous, in a way.
人間なんて みんな 醜い生き物さ｡
You're talking nonsense.
ｱﾝﾀ 言ってることが ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬだよ｡
Thank you for cooperating with our investigation.
(同心)捜査に協力 ありがとさん｡
You turned out to be quite the stray cat.
とんだ野良猫だったねぇ｡
Cats are animals that claw at things, though.
けど まぁ
猫ってのは 引っかく生き物さね｡
You hit the nail on the head.
大当たりってわけだ｡
今さら 直りゃしないよ｡
It's too late for you to change now.
But if you're down and out and need a meal in the future, come by the back of the shop.
また 食いっぱぐれたら
店の裏においでな｡
(お登勢)残りもんでも
食わせてやるよ｡
I'll let you have some leftovers.
Otose, you're a fool.
お登勢さん… ｱﾝﾀ ﾊﾞｶね｡
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)でも…｡
However...
ﾊﾞｶだって言われて怒らないとこ
初めて見たな｡
It's the first time I've seen you not get angry when someone called you a fool.
I have my moments.
気まぐれ起こすことだってあるさ｡
Since you did me a favor today. I'll let you have this month's rent free.
だから まぁ
今月の家賃くらいは➡
ﾁｬﾗにしてやるよ｡
ﾏｼﾞでか!?
You serious?!
Thanks, granny!
ありがとう ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ！
再来月から ちゃんと払うから｡
I'll be sure to pay the month after next!
Heck, I'll write off all of the late rent you owe me. And the month after next to boot.
(お登勢)なにっ
これまでの滞納分 ﾁｬﾗにしてんだ｡
(お登勢)しかも 再来月って！
やった やった！
Yippee! Yippee!
Stop trying to act cute.
(お登勢)
かわい子ぶってんじゃねえ！
A light and fleeting act of compassion...
＜軽く はかない人情だけど➡
when it touches you, you feel a warmth.
触れれば 確かに あたたかい｡
A penetrating, heartfelt song...
凍えた指先 あたためる➡
that warms one's frozen fingertips.
なぜか身に染む 心唄｡
[Location: Kabukicho]
しみるねぇ＞
[Preview]
While looking for Ham for our client,
we got involved in a tight situation.
"Harusame", the biggest crime syndicate in the galaxy?!
Who do you think you are, Frieza?! Butthead!
The next episode:
"If You're Going to Cosplay, Go All Out"
[He said looking for Ham, but it's really a person.]
["Harusame", the Biggest Crime Syndicate in the galaxy.  Going into a serious episode of Gintama?]
[Moe~]
I'm a cat-eared moe character, too.
ｱﾀｼも 一応
ﾈｺ耳 萌えｷｬﾗなんだけどﾆｮ｡